# CHYAVAN MYSORE CHANDRASHEKAR

chyavan.m.c@utexas.edu github.com/chyavan-mc • linkedin.com/in/chyavan-mc • (737) 275-8719

### **SUMMARY**

A proficient Engineering and Business student in pursuit of a graduate degree in Business Analytics. Passionate about identifying business implications beyond data, communicating and articulating ideas to technical and non-technical audiences. Creative thinker with excellent troubleshooting skills and first-hand experience in Automation, Statistical Learning, Analytics, Full-stack Development, and Database Management. Passionate about experimenting with novel technologies and taking the initiative to implement ideas.

#### **EDUCATION**

### The University of Texas at Austin

May 2023

Master of Science, Business Analytics (GPA: 4/4)

• Coursework: Advanced Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Time Series Analysis, Data Visualization, Marketing Analytics, Database Management, Optimization, Demand Analytics & Pricing, Financial Management

## JSS Science & Technology University

September 2020

Bachelor of Engineering, Electronics & Communication (CGPA: 9.11/10)

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Computer Languages: Python, SQL, R, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, C#

Technologies & Tools: Git, Scikit-learn, NLTK, OpenCV, Gurobi, Angular, Spacy, Pandas, MS SQL Server, MySQL

Project Skills: Agile (Scrum, Jira, Kanban)

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Western Digital - Software Development Engineer, Bangalore, India

August 2020 - June 2022

- Owned a module of the automation and analytical reporting Software and delivered latency improvements resulting in performance boost of up to 300% in certain cases, functional and scalable code extensions, and front-end enhancements
- Devised SQL jobs, Windows Console Applications & Services, and back-end procedures to achieve communication between internal tools and process data periodically
- Took initiative to deliver significant UI features to improve and provide a consistent user experience for worldwide internal users for the testing process of Enterprise and Client SSDs

## Western Digital - Software Development Intern, Bangalore, India

January 2020 - July 2020

• Initiated and developed an interface to automate workflow for Cadence schematics and hardware simulations resulting in more than 50% reduction of efforts and department-wide adoption

## **PROJECTS**

## **Stylized Speech Synthesis**

October 2022 - Present

• Ideated and currently working on a Generative Machine Learning model for transforming user-specified text input in a desired celebrity voice style by employing vector transformations of the celebrity voice embeddings generated in the process of speaker identification achieved with the help of Convolutional Neural Nets

## A Cornucopia of Cereals - Crowdsourced Recommendation System

September 2022 - October 2022

• Scraped data of over 1500 cereals, including user reviews, and employed user requirements of desirable attributes or similar cereals to recommend the top-3 niche products based on results from Sentiment Analysis and Word2Vec Similarity

## **Austin MetroBike Trip Prediction**

July 2022 - August 2022

• Performed multiple analyses on 1.69 million bike trips using parametric and non-parametric supervised machine learning models and predicted prospective trip volumes at MetroBike stations to provide supply management and marketing insights

# **LEADERSHIP**

- Digital Media Lead Served as the Digital Media Lead for my undergraduate university's cultural festival 'Jayciana'
- Cultural Team Led my undergraduate university's cultural team of 50+ talented individuals into a national-level cultural competition, 'Antaragni' organized by IIT-Kanpur
- Developer Student Club by Google Orchestrated cloud study jams, workshops, and boot camps, while also serving as the lead for digital media and photography teams